What you know about fear...doesn't even come close.
The Texas Chainsaw Massacre is a horror film directed by Marcus Nispel.
After picking up a traumatized young hitchhiker, five friends find themselves stalked and hunted
by a chainsaw-wielding killer and his family of equally psychopathic killers.
Erin Hardesty, played by Jessica Biel.
Morgan, played by Jonathan Tucker.
Thomas Hewitt (Leatherface), played by Andrew Bryniarski.
Pepper, played by Erica Leerhsen.
Kemper, played by Eric Balfour.
Andy, played by Mike Vogel.
The Texas Chainsaw Massacre is a 2003 American slasher film serving as a remake of Tobe Hooper's 1974 film The
Texas Chain Saw Massacre, and the fifth installment in The Texas Chainsaw Massacre franchise.
It was directed by Marcus Nispel (in his feature directorial debut), written
by Scott Kosar, and produced by Michael Bay and Mike Fleiss.
The film's ensemble cast includes Jessica Biel, Jonathan Tucker,
Erica Leerhsen, Mike Vogel, Eric Balfour, and R.
Like its source material, the plot follows a group of young adults traveling
through rural Texas who encounter Leatherface and his murderous family.
Several crew members of the original film were involved with the project: Hooper and writer Kim Henkel served as co-producers,
Daniel Pearl returned as cinematographer, and John Larroquette reprised his voice narration for the opening intertitles.
The film was released in the United States on October 17, 2003, received mixed reviews from
critics, and grossed $107 million at the box office on a budget of $9.5 million.
A prequel was released in 2006, subtitled The Beginning.
The Texas Chainsaw Massacre was the first film to be produced by Platinum Dunes, who
would go on to produce remakes of several other 20th-century horror films.
The film explores themes of suicide, sheriff, psychopath, trauma, telephone.
The tone is dark.